export const CERAMICSA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. One of the important vocations in ceramics is",
A: "block laying.",
B: "clay firing.",
C: "mould making.",
D: "stone carving.",
answer: "C. Mould making",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Promotion of ceramic wares are best done by",
A: "critics.",
B: "exhibitions.",
C: "journalists.",
D: "workshops.",
answer: "B. Exhibitions",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Raku is associated with the",
A: "funeral ceremony in Egypt.",
B: "lustre decoration in China.",
C: "tea ceremony in Japan.",
D: "vanish wares in Greece.",
answer: "C. Tea ceremony in Japan",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is poisonous when used in its raw state?",
A: "Barium oxide",
B: "Lead oxide",
C: "Sodium oxide",
D: "Tin oxide.",
answer: "B. Lead oxide",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. An appropriate material for a sackboard is",
A: "cotton.",
B: "jute.",
C: "nylon.",
D: "silk,",
answer: "B. Jute",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. During firing, a tong is appropriately used to",
A: "draw hot fired objects.",
B: "fix pyrometric cone.",
C: "lift refractory batts.",
D: "pack glazed wares.",
answer: "A. Draw hot fired objects",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following processes is used in the production of plaster of paris?",
A: "Calcination",
B: "Flocculation",
C: "Oxidation",
D: "Reduction",
answer: "A. Calcination",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Wooden bins are good containers for plastic clay because they",
A: "absorb much water.",
B: "are less expensive.",
C: "decrease shrinkage.",
D: "will not corrode.",
answer: "D. Will not corrode",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following is a glass former?",
A: "Alumina",
B: "Lead oxide",
C: "Magnesium oxide",
D: "Silica",
answer: "D. Silica",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Preliminary designing helps the ceramist to",
A: "create and produce original forms.",
B: "determine the matured temperature of wares.",
C: "ensure that only big forms are produced.",
D: "know the number of items to produce.",
answer: "A. Create and produce original forms",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The process of forcing engobe through a syringe to form a raised design is known as",
A: "casting.",
B: "glazing.",
C: "sgraffito.",
D: "trailing.",
answer: "D. Trailing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The first step in the design process is",
A: "decorating the item.",
B: "identifying a problem.",
C: "producing the item.",
D: "selecting appropriate design.",
answer: "B. Identifying a problem",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The simplest method to decorate a ware is to",
A: "carve the design on clay and paste.",
B: "cover it with an attractive glaze and fire.",
C: "incise design with a sharp pointed tool.",
D: "roll coils and create designs by pressing.",
answer: "B. Cover it with an attractive glaze and fire",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Slabs are dried on rocks to",
A: "avoid excess shrinkage.",
B: "enhance porosity.",
C: "facilitate firing.",
D: "prevent warping.",
answer: "D. Prevent warping",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Insulating bricks are made porous in order to",
A: "check corrosion,",
B: "enhance durability.",
C: "facilitate cooling.",
D: "retain heat.",
answer: "D. Retain heat",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Identify the clays which are suitable for modelling.\nI. Kaoli\nIl. Bentonit\nIIl. Earthenwar\nIV. Stoneware",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "I, Il and IV only",
D: "I, If and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A bonding material in slab work is",
A: "cement.",
B: "coil.",
C: "plaster.",
D: "slip.",
answer: "D. Slip",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. How relevant is it to finish a cast ware by fettling?",
A: "Joints are revealed",
B: "Moulds are carefully detached",
C: "Mould marks are removed",
D: "Objects are easily decorated",
answer: "C. Mould marks are removed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In throwing, the foam is used for",
A: "centring.",
B: "mopping.",
C: "opening.",
D: "texturing.",
answer: "A. Centring",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Slabbing is a forming method that requires the use of",
A: "armature.",
B: "guide sticks.",
C: "kidney.",
D: "press moulds.",
answer: "B. Guide sticks",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Lumps of clay are broken down by",
A: "coiling.",
B: "kneading.",
C: "rolling.",
D: "wedging.",
answer: "B. Kneading",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Why is clay washed? To",
A: "make it more plastic.",
B: "make it more porous.",
C: "reduce shrinkage.",
D: "remove foreign matter.",
answer: "D. Remove foreign matter",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Wax resist, sgraffito and mishima are examples of",
A: "incised decoration.",
B: "impressed decoration,",
C: "underglaze decoration.",
D: "slip decoration.",
answer: "C. Underglaze decoration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The sprigging decoration is done by",
A: "making designs on leatherhard pots with pointed tools.",
B: "polishing the surface of leatherhard clay objects.",
C: "pressing clay in a mould, removing and fixing on a pot with slip.",
D: "using tools to make patterns on wet pots by pressing gently.",
answer: "C. Pressing clay in a mould, removing and fixing on a pot with slip",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The application of wax in decoration",
A: "improves colour of glaze.",
B: "improves the absorption of glaze.",
C: "makes colours look pale.",
D: "resist glaze on ware.",
answer: "D. Resist glaze on ware",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Mishima is applied in the",
A: "biscuit state.",
B: "bonedry state.",
C: "glost state.",
D: "leatherhard state.",
answer: "D. Leatherhard state",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In reduction firing, wares",
A: "appear small in size.",
B: "develop pinholes.",
C: "look bright and clean.",
D: "look dull and dark.",
answer: "D. Look dull and dark",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Identify the causes of cracking from the following.\nI. Uneven drying\nIl. Even thickness\nIII. Rapid rate of drying\nIV. Excessive warping",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "I, If and IV only",
D: "II, TU and IV only",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Embossed decoration can also be termed",
A: "inlay.",
B: "intaglio.",
C: "relief.",
D: "sgraffito.",
answer: "C. Relief",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Select a disadvantage of excessive shrinkage of clay.",
A: "Crazing",
B: "Melting",
C: "Warping",
D: "Wobbling",
answer: "C. Warping",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The justification for smoking fired wares is to",
A: "check cracking and warping.",
B: "ensure maximum maturing temperature,",
C: "make them lighter and porous,",
D: "increase their aesthetic value.",
answer: "D. Increase their aesthetic value",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Low temperature glaze include",
A: "ash, alkaline and lead.",
B: "borax, alkaline and ash.",
C: "lead, ash and borax.",
D: "lead, borax and alkaline.",
answer: "A. Ash, alkaline, and lead",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of these is an example of a stabilizer?",
A: "Alumina",
B: "Borax",
C: "Feldspar",
D: "Silica",
answer: "A. Alumina",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The term fixed cost is used to describe expenditure that",
A: "change all the time.",
B: "does not relate directly to production.",
C: "has accumulated over time.",
D: "relates directly to production.",
answer: "B. Does not relate directly to production",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. What role does flux play in glazes? It",
A: "adds colour to the glaze",
B: "forms the glassy parts of glaze",
C: "helps fit of glaze",
D: "lowers melting temperature",
answer: "D. Lowers melting temperature",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The price of a pot is usually higher than its cost of production because of the",
A: "size of the pot.",
B: "aesthetic value of pot.",
C: "margin of profit.",
D: "production technique used.",
answer: "C. Margin of profit",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Siting brick and tile studio close to the source of raw material",
A: "add value to the products.",
B: "cuts down transportation cost.",
C: "makes it grow faster.",
D: "protects its major input.",
answer: "B. Cuts down transportation cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A ceramic tripod on which glazed wares are placed in a kiln is the",
A: "prop.",
B: "saggar.",
C: "spur.",
D: "stilt.",
answer: "D. Stilt",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Extrusion is a method of pressing clay",
A: "into a mould to take its shape.",
B: "on the potter’s wheel to centre it.",
C: "through a machine to extract excess water.",
D: "through a machine to produce bricks,",
answer: "D. Through a machine to produce bricks",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of these materials is most suitable for a sketch model?",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Cement",
C: "Kaolin",
D: "Plasticine",
answer: "D. Plasticine",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]